ShinY
深影
本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址http://shinybbs.vip
■
《小谢尔顿》前情回顾...
Previously on Young Sheldon...
大家好 我是谢尔顿·库珀 欢迎收看
Hello. I'm Sheldon Cooper,
欢迎收看 "谢尔顿为什么要去上大学"
and this is Why Sheldon Cooper Should Go to College.
ShinY
深影
■
ShinY
深影
我坚定的认为
I firmly believe
我已经准备好跨入我学术生活的下一步
that I'm ready for this next step in my academic life.
■
翻译： Katja_x  慢慢  鲜虾鱼板面
看来我们的孩子要去上大学了
I guess our baby's going to college.
■
校对：  二拾     压制： 飒白恬
不是针对你 但我确实不想结婚
So I don't want to get married. It's nothing personal.
我为你和你的家人做了那么多事
After everything that I've done for you and your family.
因为你给了我外孙工作
You give my grandson a job
所以我就要和你结婚吗
so I'm supposed to marry you?
就当我没说
Well, you can forget I even asked.
ShinY
深影
■
糟了
Oh, no.
我搞砸了
I screwed up.
你被开除了
You're fired.
谁叫你炒我外孙鱿鱼
Here's for firing my grandson.
混蛋
Jackass!
ShinY
深影
我一直不理解 为什么其他孩子
I never understood why kids didn't like
不喜欢被叫到校长办公室去
being sent to the principal's office.
我就很喜欢
I thought it was great.
谢尔顿 你真是个出色的孩子
Sheldon, you are a remarkable young man.
谢谢 你也是个出色的老头
Thanks, and you're a remarkable old man.
谢尔顿
Sheldon.
您确定他已经修满所有的学分了吗
So you sure he's got all the credits he needs?
是的 他修完了所有应修课程
Yeah, between his coursework and his AP tests,
通过了跳级测试 所有要求都达标了
he's met all of his academic requirements.
甚至体育课的成绩都很不错
He even managed to get a good grade in P.E.
靠举报那些在器材后面抽烟的学生
I earned extra credit snitching on kids
我挣了不少额外的学分
who were smoking behind the equipment shed.
这一年我都不用买烟了
I don't have to buy cigarettes for a year.
所以他真的能毕业了吗
So he's really good to graduate?
当然 我告诉你
He sure is. I got to tell ya,
那些把高中读完的学生
usually when kids leave school after two years,
压根不是去上大学的
it's not for college.
要不进监狱 要不进产房
It's for prison or pregnancy.
小乔和米西说不定就是这样
Well, between Georgie and Missy, we may hit the trifecta.
乔治
George!
我并不是支持这样
Well, I'm not rooting for it.
只是这是有可能发生的
It's just a thing that could happen.
还有一件事
One other bit of business.
鉴于你要提前毕业
Since you're graduating early,
而且是班里的尖子生
and you're top of the class,
你就是我们的毕业致辞代表了
that makes you our valedictorian.
干得漂亮 孩子
Way to go, buddy!
我真为你骄傲
I'm so proud of you, baby.
你看起来很吃惊
You seem surprised.
是啊 这是个不小的荣誉
Well, it's quite an accomplishment.
成为这个学校的尖子生吗
Being top of the class in this school?
我不觉得这是个荣誉
I don't think so.
我们会想你的
We're really gonna miss you.
小谢尔顿
第四季 第1集
我要走了 你肯定很难过吧
I imagine my leaving will be hard for you.
当然了 和小屁孩做朋友
Oh, yeah, being best friends
对我找女朋友可太有帮助了
with a little kid really boosted my game with the ladies.
有道理 我可是打破尴尬的好话题
Makes sense. I'm a conversation starter.
你想想 这个桌子以后就是你一个人的了
Just think. You'll have this table all to yourself.
我加入了爵士乐队
Actually, I joined the jazz band.
他们的自助餐厅里有自己的桌子
Those guys have their own table in the cafeteria.
他们挺酷的
They're pretty cool.
鼓手还留着山羊胡呢
The drummer's even got a goatee.
幸好我在你成为瘾君子前就认识你了
Well, I'm glad I knew you before you became a heroin addict.
我的护目镜呢
Where are my safety goggles?
我今天没带橙子
I don't have no orange today.
不 我待会有实验课
No, I have a lab later.
你就像别人一样用公用护目镜吧
Just use the room goggles like everyone else.
然后被传染上眉毛的虱子吗
And risk eyebrow lice?
虱子可不光喜欢待在头上 小谭
They don't just like head hair, Tam.
肯定在我的储物柜里
They must be in my locker.
不许吃我的花生酱三明治
Don't eat my fluffernutter!
我不会的
I won't.
"不许吃我的花生酱三明治"
"Don't eat my fluffernutter."
你好
Hello.
谢谢你见我
Thank you for seeing me.
看到我分手后的杰作时 你应该笑不出来吧
You might not be so happy I did by the time we're done.
好吧 我先说一句
All right, let me start by saying
我觉得我欠你一个道歉
that I owe you an apology.
你道完歉就走也行
You can finish with an apology, too.
很抱歉我们吵了一架
I'm sorry we had a fight. I'm...
抱歉我没控制好我的脾气
I'm really sorry I lost my temper,
抱歉我把气撒在了小乔身上
and I'm very sorry that I took it out on Georgie.
这很不好
That wasn't great.
但我想你知道 我在试着改
But I want you to know that I'm trying to change.
是啊 人们都会改变自己的
'Cause that's what people do... They change.
我是认真的
I mean it.
我受够了自己古怪暴躁的脾气
You know, I'm tired of being a cranky old bastard.
别人也受够了
It's tiring for everybody else, too.
你能不说了吗
Would you please?
抱歉 你继续
Sorry. Go ahead.
我承认我错了 换做以前的我绝不会承认
I'm admitting I was wrong, and that's not something I do.
你想要我怎么做
What do you want from me?
再给我一次机会
One more chance.
我不确定...
I don't know.
求你了
Oh, come on.
为了买这些紫色的花 我跑了三家店
I went to three stores to find these purple flowers.
花很漂亮
They are pretty.
没你漂亮
They're not as pretty as you.
我的天...
Oh, God.
安全别针 安全剪刀
Safety pins, safety scissors,
就是没有安全护目镜
no safety goggles.
你有看见一副安全护目镜吗
Did you happen to see a pair of safety goggles?
谢尔顿 我们正在考试呢
Sheldon, we're in the middle of a test.
抱歉
Sorry.
我不能把答案告诉你
I can't give you the answer,
但你的答案还差得远呢
but what you have is not even close.
出去
Out!
这种事常发生
These things happen.
我母亲在岁数很小时怀的我
My mother had me when she was young.
不好意思打断你们
Sorry to interrupt.
我找不到我的护目镜了
I can't find my safety goggles.
好吧 不在这
Well, they're not here.
我必须找到
I have to find them.
做好防护是最重要的
Nothing's more important than protection!
爸 你得载我回家
Dad, you need to take me home.
为什么 怎么了
Why? What's the matter?
我没带我的护目镜 我们走吧
I don't have my safety goggles. Let's go.
谢尔顿 我很忙
Sheldon, I'm busy.
你就是在看电视啊
You're just watching TV.
我是在回顾比赛的录像带
I'm reviewing game tape.
所以你都知道结果如何了
So you know how it ends.
我待会在车上见
I'll meet you at the car.
谢尔顿 我不会载你回家的
Sheldon, I'm not driving you home.
我二十分钟后要去训练了
I got practice in 20 minutes.
那就给打给妈妈 让她送过来
Then call Mom and tell her to bring them to me.
她也在工作
She's working, too.
但我需要我的护目镜啊
But I need my goggles!
那就用课上的那副
Then use the ones in class.
我不想听到眉虱那一套
And I don't want to hear about eyebrow lice.
课上那副我用太大了
The ones in class are too big for me.
如果它掉下来 我眼睛出了什么事怎么办
What if they fall off and something happens to my eyes?
如果我失明了 我就需要一条导盲犬
If I go blind, I'll need a Seeing Eye dog,
但是我怕狗
and I'm scared of dogs.
嘿
Hey!
你上了大学以后也要这样吗
Is this how you plan on acting when you get to college?
不是
No.
很好
Good,
因为你要学会自己处理这样的事情
'cause you're gonna need to handle stuff like this on your own.
我可以的
I can handle it.
希望如此
I hope so.
最后那天我用了课上的护目镜
I ended up using the class goggles that day
而且没有得眉虱
and did not get eyebrow lice.
但是八个月后
But eight months later,
我确实感染了轻微的结膜炎
I did contract a mild case of pink eye.
这两者有相关性吗
Were the two events related?
本科学家说有
This scientist says yes.
你觉得我能在十分钟之内
Do you think I can make it from one end
从学校的一头到另一头
of the college campus to the other in under ten minutes,
还包括一次如厕吗
including a bathroom break?
我不知道 必须去厕所吗
I don't know. How important is the bathroom break?
非常需要
Very.
课程表是按照成年人的膀胱设计的
The class schedules are designed for fully-grown bladders,
而我的还是儿童款的
and mine is child-sized.
那就别把你的课安排的太紧凑
Then don't put your classes so close together.
好吧 只能这样
Well, it's either this
或者把我的实验课挪到周二下午
or I move my labs to Tuesday afternoons.
那不好吗
Is that bad?
是啊 那时候正在播质子教授
Yes. That's when Professor Proton is on.
好吧 我们会把它录下来你可以之后看
Well, we'll tape it, and you can watch it later.
但我要是有一堆作业 第二天还没来得及看
But what if I have a lot of homework and can't get to it until the next day
我们班上的孩子给我剧透怎么办
and one of the kids in my class spoils the episode for me?
谢尔顿 有人给你剧透过质子教授吗
Sheldon, has anyone ever spoiled Professor Proton for you?
- 没有 - 有人和你聊过质子教授吗
- No. - Has anyone even talked to you about Professor Proton?
你算吗
Do you count?
不算
No.
那没有
Then no.
很感谢再给我一次机会
Thanks again for giving me another shot.
我的荣幸
Oh, my pleasure.
我还有些东西要给你
And I got something else for you.
谢谢 但是为什么
Thank you, but why?
嗯 我在努力学会原谅他人
Well, I'm trying to get better at forgiving people.
很高兴听到你这么说
Well, I'm glad to hear you say that,
因为就是我昨晚朝你店里扔鸡蛋的
'cause I'm the one who egged your store last night.
是你干的
That was you?
我和我姥姥
Well, me and Meemaw.
没事
It's okay.
我原谅你了
I forgive you.
很好 再次感谢你给我这些钱
Cool. Thanks again for the money.
原谅别人真是糟糕透了
Mm, forgiving people sucks.
保佑我们 上帝 赐我们食物
Bless us, Lord, for the food we are about to receive,
保佑做食物的人
and bless the hands that prepared it.
感谢你 帮小乔要回了他的工作
And thank you for Georgie getting his job back.
阿门
Amen.
戴尔真是个好人
That was nice of Dale.
我知道 他还原谅了我朝他店里扔鸡蛋
I know. He even forgave me for egging his store.
你扔鸡蛋不叫我
You went egging without me?
小乔治·库珀
Georgie Cooper!
戴尔已经原谅了我 上帝也必须原谅我
Dale already forgave me, and God has to.
你不能对我发脾气
You can't get mad.
扎心了
Ha. Burn.
等下等下
Oh. Hold on. Hold on.
请坐 夫人
Your chair, milady.
夫人
"Milady"?
这是哪的话
Where did that come from?
我不知道
I don't know.
我脑子里
My brain.
二位要点些酒水吗
Can I get y'all started with some drinks?
好的 玛格丽特
Yeah. Uh, margaritas?
分着喝吧
Split a pitcher?
不了 我不喝了
Mm, no, I think I'm okay.
今晚想喝啤酒了吗
More of a beer night?
不 不是
No, not really.
这段时间先不喝酒了
I'm gonna take a little break.
我喝水就行了
I'll just stick with water.
真的吗
Really?
你知道的 我喝酒之后
Well, you know, I don't do my best thinking
不能很好的思考
after I've been drinking.
那我还要喝酒吗
Should I not get one, then?
没事 你继续
No, no, you go ahead.
我不想让氛围变得奇怪
I don't want it to get weird.
我可以待会儿再来
I can come back.
不不不 就给她来一杯玛格丽特
No, no. Hey, just bring her a margarita.
不
No, don't.
我坚持
I insist.
我不想要
I don't want one.
不 你想要的
Yeah, you do.
你越来越奇怪了
It's getting weird.
要不你待会再来吧
Maybe come back.
米西 你和谢尔顿的毕业派对想怎么办
Missy, how would you and Sheldon like a graduation party?
为什么米西也有毕业派对
Why would Missy have a graduation party?
因为我要从小学毕业了
'Cause I'm graduating elementary school.
这也算吗
That counts?
当然算了
Of course it counts.
这是件大事 她要上新学校了
Yes, it's a big deal. She's going to a new school.
会有新朋友 新老师
New friends, new teachers.
就是没有新衣服 因为我们穷
Same clothes 'cause we're poor.
我们不穷
We're not poor.
那我能买新衣服吗
So I can get new clothes?
但我们也不是富豪
We're not rich, either.
我得忍受两场毕业典礼吗
Do I really got to sit through two graduations?
当然了 这对你的弟弟妹妹来说是件大事
Yes. It is a special day for your brother and your sister.
我要进行毕业致辞
I'm giving the valedictorian speech.
我要和一群小孩一起唱
And I'm singing "This Land Is Your Land"
"这是你的土地"
with a bunch of other kids.
美国著名民谣
我们同样的为你们俩自豪
And we are proud of you both equally.
你们猜怎么着
Guess what.
当地新闻台想要报道
The local news wants
谢尔顿做毕业致辞的事
to do story on Sheldon being valedictorian.
太棒了 不是吗
Isn't that great?
怎么了
What?
干杯
Cheers.
好喝吗
How is it?
不错 你的呢
Good. Yours?
有点水
A little watery.
你让小乔回去工作
I want to tell you how much I appreciate you
我非常感谢你
giving Georgie his job back.
我不是只为你一个人这么做的
Well, I didn't do it just for you.
这是我该做的正确的事
It was the right thing to do.
我甚至原谅了他砸我店鸡蛋的事
I even forgave him for egging the store.
他用鸡蛋砸你的店
He egged your store?
这个淘气鬼
That rascal!
我知道你也参与了
I know you did it, too.
没错
Okay, I did.
你去教堂 对吗
You go to church, don't you?
是的 在我没有宿醉的时候
Yeah, when I'm not hungover.
哪天我和你一起去吧
Well, maybe I'll go with you sometime.
你吗 你认真的
Really? You?
是的 我觉得信教或许对我有好处
Yeah, I was thinking a little religion might do me some good.
不错
Well, good for you.
我还以为今晚只是来吃墨西哥肉卷的呢
I was thinking it was a fajita night.
你的女儿研究圣经的 对吗
Your daughter runs a Bible study, doesn't she?
是啊
Uh-huh.
第二天 当天电视台来参访我和我的家人
The next day, the local news showed up to interview me and my family,
这听起来也许很了不起
which may sound impressive,
但这和报道拿着得克萨斯州形状的薯片的
but this is the same local news that covered a potato chip
是同一家电视台
shaped like Texas.
自然一点就行 就当是在聊天
So act natural. We're just having a chat.
我会问几个
I'm gonna ask y'all a few questions
关于谢尔顿从高中毕业的问题
about Sheldon's high school graduation.
我也要毕业了
I'm graduating, also.
是吗 你也从高中毕业吗
Really? You're graduating from high school, too?
不 小学
No, elementary school.
哦
Oh.
我们班要唱"这是你的土地"
My class is singing "This Land Is Your Land."
你想听吗
Want to hear it?
这片土地属于你
This Land Is Your Land.
我能在电视上邀请我女朋友去毕业舞会吗
Hey, can I ask my girlfriend to the prom on TV?
这肯定会让她吓一跳
It would blow her mind.
这里是库珀一家
We're here with the Cooper family.
玛丽 乔治 还有十一岁的谢尔顿
Mary, George and 11-year-old Sheldon,
他会在梅德福高中的毕业典礼上致辞
who's going to be Medford High School's valedictorian.
谢尔顿爸妈 你们一定很自豪吧
Mom and Dad, you must be so proud.
当然
Oh, very proud.
我们为我们所有的孩子骄傲
But we're proud of all of our children.
她必须这么说
She has to say that.
我有点担心不能看质子教授
I was a little worried about missing
但我打算把它录下来
Professor Proton, but I'm going to tape it
然后晚上去看
and watch it at night.
我上大学之后
Once I'm in college,
能推迟到八点半睡觉吗
can we push my bedtime to 8:30?
别在上电视的时候提这个好吗 宝贝
Let's talk bedtime when we're not on the news, honey.
我整个夏天都在重新安排我的如厕日程
I'm sure it'll work out since I have all summer
我觉得这肯定没问题的
to recalibrate my bathroom schedule.
这个也别提
Let's not talk about that, either.
有这样一个特别的孩子
So what's it like being the parents of
你们父母有何感想
such a special child?
快拿走 快拿走
Get it away! Get it away!
真神奇
Fascinating.
每一天都很幸福
Every day's a blessing.
谢尔顿 告诉我们
Sheldon, tell us what you're gonna miss
你会最怀念高中的什么
the most about high school.
没有
Nothing.
真的吗
Really?
不怀念你的老师和朋友吗
Not your teachers, your friends?
我只有一个朋友
I only have one friend.
但我觉得他不会想我
And I don't think he's gonna miss me
因为他已经找到了一起吃午餐的人
because he already found other people to have lunch with.
我觉得他肯定会想你的
Oh, I'm sure he'll miss you.
我可以说我能改到晚上看质子教授
And I said I'm okay with watching Professor Proton
但那不是真的
at night, but that'll never work.
我会困的 大家都知道
I get overtired... Everybody knows that!
要不把摄像机关了吧
Maybe we could turn the camera off.
那天我找不到我的护目镜
And the other day, I couldn't find my safety goggles
我在学校崩溃了 我爸问我
and I freaked out in school, and my dad asked
我上了大学之后是不是也这样
is this how I plan on acting when I get to college,
我说不 但这可能是假话
and I said no, but it probably is
虽然我很聪明 但我也只是个孩子
because even though I'm smart, I'm just a little boy!
要不就到这里吧
I think we have enough.
咔
Cut.
喝吧孩子
Here you go, baby.
我不知道我明年是否还能去上大学
I don't know if I can go to college next year.
你在跟我开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?!
乔治
George.
兄弟 我知道你很低落
Buddy, I know you're upset.
但你在逗我吗
But are you kidding me?
别听他的
Don't listen to him.
不要有压力
There is no pressure.
如果你想在高中再待一年
If you want to spend another year in high school,
一切取决于你
that is your decision.
我不知道
I don't know.
我可以离开一会儿吗
May I be excused?
当然
Uh, of course.
我们都支持你 兄弟
We support you, buddy!
我明白
I get it.
什么
What do you get?
为什么你不想去大学
Why you don't want to go to college.
我不信
I doubt that you do.
你害怕一切都会变得不一样
You're scared everything's gonna be different
这会很艰难
and it'll be hard.
然后就会怀念以前的生活
And you're gonna miss the way that it was.
你怎么知道
How do you know that?
因为这就是我现在的感受
'Cause that's how I feel.
你在害怕吗
You're scared?
是的
Yeah.
那么我们该怎么办呢
So what do we do?
害怕 但还是要去做吧
I guess be scared and do it anyway.
我很欣慰你能和我感同身受
It's comforting to know that you feel the same way that I do.
所以我才这么说 笨蛋
That's why I said it, dumbass.
妈妈
Mom?
爸爸
Dad?
怎么了 宝贝
Yeah, baby?
我准备好毕业了
I'm ready to graduate.
晚安
Good night.
因为我支持他了
That's because I supported him.
接下来的小致辞者 不需要任何介绍
Our next young speaker needs no introduction,
但依然阻止不了他写下一篇 逼我朗读
but that didn't stop him from writing one and making me read it.
"冷知识"
"Fun fact."
同感
I hear you.
"Valedictorian"这个词
"The word 'valedictorian'
valedictorian:(毕业典礼上)致告别辞的最优生 毕业生代表
来源于拉丁语"valedicere"
is from the Latin 'valedicere,'
"意思是'说再见'"
"Meaning 'to say farewell.'
"主要在美国
"It is primarily used in the United States,
加拿大 菲律宾和亚美尼亚使用"
Canada, the Philippines and Armenia."
也许这个冷知识在亚美尼亚更有趣
Maybe that fact's more fun in Armenia.
下面欢迎你们的优秀毕业生代表
Please welcome your valedictorian,
谢尔顿·库珀
Sheldon Cooper.
太棒了 谢利
Yay, Shelly!
大家好
Hello.
我不太习惯在人群面前讲话
I'm not very comfortable speaking in front of crowds.
但是有一个技巧可以减少怯场
But there's a technique to reduce stage fright
就是专注于观众中的一个人
by focusing on one person in the audience
只对他们演讲
and delivering your speech just to them.
这就是我今天要做的
That's what I'll be doing today.
如果不是因为这个人
If it weren't for this person,
我现在也不会在这里
I wouldn't be here right now.
他们教会了我很多
They've taught me a lot,
正是以他们为榜样 我才有了勇气
and it's by their example that I found the courage
继续前进 翻开我生命中激动人心的新篇章
to move forward into this new and exciting chapter of my life.
米西...
Missy...
这是写给你的
this is for you.
改变是可怕的
Change can be scary,
但我知道我们会没事的...
but I know we're going to be fine...
因为就像你说的
because like you said,
"害怕是正常的
"It's okay to be scared.
但我们还是要勇往直前"
We just have to do it anyway."
所以如果我的毕业生同学们 对未来感到紧张
So if any of my fellow graduates are nervous about the future,
要知道你们并不孤单
know that you're not alone.
我建议你们都要像我的双胞胎姐姐一样勇敢
I suggest you all try to be as brave as my twin sister.
我就是这样做的
That's my plan.
米西
Missy,
我希望我能给你一些关于初中的建议
I wish I could give you advice about middle school,
但我太聪明了 没用上
but I was so smart, I skipped it.
如果你能上高中 我们再聊
If you make it to high school, we'll talk.
谢谢
Thank you.
第二天
The following day,
我参加了姐姐的小学毕业典礼
I attended my sister's elementary school graduation.
她没有给我演讲
She didn't deliver a speech to me,
但当她唱"这是你的土地"时
but she did make eye contact
给了我眼神交流
while she sang "This Land Is Your Land."
从红衫林到墨西哥湾
From the Redwood forests, to the Gulf stream waters.
这片土地属于你和我
This land was made for you and me.
那天晚些时候
Later that day,
他们为我和姐姐举办了毕业派对
we had a graduation party for me and my sister.
我通常不喜欢派对
I don't normally care for parties,
但这次还不赖
but this one wasn't so bad.
谁要吃蛋糕啊
Who's ready for cake?
我
Me!
我们要做祷告吗
Hey, should we say grace?
见鬼 好啊 让我们手牵手
Heck, yeah! Let's hold hands.
真棒 来做祷告吧
Oh, cool. Let's say grace.
戴尔邀请了耶稣来参加派对
Dale invited Jesus to the party,
虽然他不在我的宾客名单上 但没关系
and while he wasn't on my guest list, it was okay
因为这让我妈妈很高兴
because it made my mom happy.
祝福我们的朋友和家人...
And bless our friends and family...
事实上 这是我目前去过的最好的毕业派对
In fact, it was the best graduation party I had ever been to,
直到我参加了我儿子莱纳德·库珀的毕业典礼
until the one we had for my son, Leonard Cooper.
阿门
Amen.
蛋糕
Cake!
我本来想叫他
I wanted his name to be
■
更多精彩 请登录深影论坛 shinybbs.vip
深影字幕组微博 weibo.com/syfansub
莱纳德·"尼莫伊"·库珀
Leonard "Nimoy" Cooper,
但是艾米不让
but Amy wouldn't let me.
我能让你取名莱纳德就高兴着吧
Be happy I let you name him Leonard!
好的 好的
Okay, okay!
■
关注深影字幕组
微信公众号，更
多影视资讯，等
你来发现
爱你
Love you.
我也爱你
Love you, too.